♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 22=
My lord,
I just found out some crucial news.
What is it?
I just overheard outside
the Abbot's room
that Jinshan Temple's Abbot
is the key to the seal.
Once he dies,
the seal will be lifted.
Then why didn't you just kill him?
There is a barrier in his room,
so I couldn't kill him.
Rise.
I'll tell you what to do.
I'm back.
Where is everyone?
Nobody's coming out to welcome me?
Why are you yelling
so early in the morning?
So noisy! Keep quiet or get out.
Get out?
Why should I
get out?
I'm in. I'm out.
I'm in.
When did you invalidate the contract?
As the head disciple of Jinshan Temple,
how could I be bossed around?
From now on,
I'm a free man.
A free man?
By invalidating the contract,
you think I can't boss you around?
You, come here.
I'm not coming over.
I'm out.
I'm out again. I'm out.
- Come here!
- I'm out again.
- Get over here!
- Come on, catch me.
I'm not coming over.
Come on.
Get over here!
Come on, come over here.
Fahai!
- I'm not coming over.
- Did you hear me?
Come over here.
No way!
Fahai, how dare you!
Don't! Not the face!
I am so sorry, really!
I won't do it again!
Come over here!
I'm sorry.
I won't do it again! Stop it!
That's the situation.
Master told me to warn you two
not to use spiritual powers
in the mortal realm.
If his back acts up again,
he'll come to catch you two.
Can your master even catch me?
Let me tell you,
Master is very powerful.
Master told me to ask you
if the Drake Demon King
could be easily killed,
why did Jinshan Temple
only suppress him?
But if his true body
is sealed in the Forbidden Area,
then how could he control
my evil self to do his bidding?
Right. How did he do that?
Can anyone go
to that Forbidden Area at will?
Of course not.
Then how could your master not know?
Come sit here.
I shall impart the powers to you.
That shouldn't be.
What is wrong, Master?
Perhaps the time hasn't come yet.
Why are you keeping me in suspense?
What's wrong?
Fahai, though you're a bit clumsy,
you are resilient.
Though you're mischievous,
you have great potential.
Though sometimes
you can't tell good from evil,
you are still
my most pure-hearted disciple.
Master,
am I really that bad?
Focus on the compliments I gave you.
I only hope you can comprehend
the great Dao soon,
achieve enlightenment in Buddhism,
and protect the peace
of the people in my stead.
Master, I can do it now.
What did you...
Amitabha.
Go now.
Remember, without my order,
do not come back.
But Master...
Go.
I am tired.
Don't stay and disturb my meditation.
Hey! What are you doing?
Just go.
Master, I'm leaving then.
I'm leaving, Master.
We should go to Jinshan Temple.
But Master told me
that without his order,
I cannot go back.
Think about it.
Why did your master
impart the powers to you?
He's always being so mysterious.
He must have his reasons
for not letting me go back.
Something's off with the seal.
Everyone, take your artifacts.
Go to the Forbidden Area!
- Yes!
Why does it light up?
I-I don't know.
An abnormal movement in Leifeng Pagoda.
Did something go wrong with the seal?
Abbot is the key to the seal.
If something happens to the seal,
Abbot will be in danger.
Let's go and check.
Let's go.
Without my order,
you can't come back.
Why? Jinshan Temple is my home.
I only hope you can comprehend
the great Dao soon,
achieve enlightenment in Buddhism,
and protect the peace
of the people in my stead.
Remember, without my order,
do not come back.
But Master...
Go.
I am tired.
Master!
Old Monk, you came quite fast.
You sealed me here
together for 300 years,
making me suffer a lot.
But today, I will break this seal
and turn this world to ashes!
Don't panic, everyone!
Reinforce the seal with me!
- Yes!
I guard you here
by my late master's order
to redeem you.
Redeem me?
When I was cultivating
in the mortal realm,
you weren't even born yet.
Who are you to redeem me?
Though you've cultivated
for 1,000 years,
you slaughtered living beings
and devoured cores.
You walk on a demonic path
paved with blood and bones.
The Dao will never tolerate it!
Dao?
The Dao is nothing
but rules made by the strong.
When I achieve supreme power,
I shall be the Dao.
By then,
whoever I send to death
will go to death.
Whoever I grant ascension
will ascend.
Vile creature!
Stubborn fool!
Go down the mountain and tell Fahai
not to come back to Jinshan Temple!
- Master!
- Go now!
Karma will come around.
You will reap what you sow.
Today, I'll show you
what the karma really is!
Oh, no!
My lord, congratulations
on breaking the seal!
Break!
Why?
Didn't you say that once Abbot died,
the seal would be lifted?
I-I heard Abbot say
that he's the key to the seal,
and once he died, the seal would break.
How could this happen?
Mercy, My lord!
I gathered demonic energy for you
with utter loyalty.
I never keep any for myself.
Please trust me, My lord!
Utter loyalty?
You kept demonic energy for yourself.
Do you really think I don't know that?
My lord, I was wrong!
Since you know you were wrong,
use your life
to pave the way for my ascension.
Use your body
to help me shatter this array.
I only wanted to live.
What did I do wrong?
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪